(relaxing dance music)
- All right, I have
good news and bad news.
What do you want first?
The good news, great.
Good call.
It's still a Pixel.
The bad news?
It is still a Pixel.
(lively dance music)
See, the Pixel 10 has had some high hopes
and some hype behind it
for the past couple months.
You know, it's the 10th generation.
It could be special.
The first one with a TSMC
chip could be special.
Some other things could be
revamped alongside Android 16.
Like, it was looking really promising
to potentially reboot
the whole Pixel thing,
to finally have it really
competing with flagships.
Now instead, it is very
much all the things we liked
and all the things we disliked
about the Pixel already,
but the competing with flagships part
is coming in the form of a
mainstream marketing push.
A Jimmy Fallon presentation,
a Jonas Brothers music video.
I can't say I would've spent
the money the exact same way
if I was in charge of the Pixel program,
but hey, that's why I'm the reviewer
and they're the Google executives.
So, unlike the event, let's
just focus on the phones.
So, this thing is very similar
to last year in design,
in materials, and in character.
Like the camera visor,
the glossy glass back
with the satin aluminum sides,
and vice versa on the Pro phones.
Even as an enthusiast about this stuff,
you could probably show me a Pixel 9,
and unless I knew exactly which
one was the new gray color,
it could be easily
mistaken for the new one.
And to me, honestly, that's fine.
I love this design.
The camera bar is nice
for holding the phone.
It gathers some dust, sure,
but you'll probably also
have a case on your phone.
Great, click-y buttons, great haptics.
All of these things are
still true about the Pixel.
The bad news though, is that
the things that the Pixels
of the past have been lacking,
this one is still lacking.
Pixels have never had the biggest numbers
or the most bleeding-edge hardware.
And these Pixel 10s are still Pixels,
so they don't have super fast charging.
They don't have a brand new
massive silicon carbon battery.
They don't have huge new camera sensors
or record-breaking displays.
My personal biggest
annoyance with the Pixel 9
was the optical under
screen fingerprint reader
was kinda slow.
This Pixel 10 actually does have
an ultrasonic fingerprint reader now,
and it's faster than Pixel 9,
but just a slight beat
behind the other ultrasonic flagships now.
But that counts as technically new.
So, hey, while we're at
it, here's everything
that's technically new with the Pixel 10s
and my take on them.
The main new thing is we
get a full triple cameras
on the base phone, and I'll
get more into the quality
of those cameras in a minute,
so that is a nice inclusion.
After that, it's a bunch
of subtle things that sort
of combine to make it feel
a little more flagship-y
but without actually leapfrogging
into ultra phone territory.
So, the fingerprint reader, like I said,
is ultrasonic now and slightly faster.
And the display that it's built into
is a bit brighter too, so
it looks better outdoors.
The bezels didn't get thinner,
but there's little grills now
over the slightly better speakers
at the bottom of the phone
that are color matched to the metal now.
Cool.
And the physical SIM card
tray is now completely gone.
This phone in the US is eSIM
only, which I don't like.
eSIM support, great.
Forcing me to use eSIM?
Not my favorite thing.
Only the carriers win with this.
And to be fair, maybe
I'm over-indexing this
just a little bit because
I test a lot of phones.
I move my physical SIM card really quickly
between lots of phones.
It takes, like, 10 seconds to switch
and test something out real quick.
So, I don't like this at
all, but yeah, eSIM only.
The batteries are about
200 milliamp hours larger
in these phones across the lineup.
That's a nice win.
But the internals that are
gonna make a real difference
that people are actually gonna care about
are Tensor and Pixel Snap.
So, all right, we gotta talk
about this new Tensor chip.
Google phones, for years,
have used off-the-shelf
chips from Qualcomm,
which made sense, they were great.
And then the Pixel 6 was the first one
to use their in-house
design Tensor chip instead.
And the promise of Tensor
was never really clear,
but the idea was to give
Google much more control
over these chips and for optimizing
for exactly what they
wanna get out of a Pixel.
The thing is, the first
Tensor chip wasn't that good.
Actually, it was so weak that
it had people considering
if they should have even left
Qualcomm in the first place.
But, you know, we gotta let 'em cook
for a little bit, right?
Let them develop this idea.
And so, a couple generations in,
all of these first few Tensor chips
were sort of co-designed
with Google and Samsung,
and it was heavily based
off of an Exynos chip
and actually still fabricated by Samsung.
So, fast forward to today,
the Pixel 10 is powered
by a Tensor G5 chip,
the first version of a totally
Google-designed Tensor chip
on a three-nanometer process
and manufactured straight by TSMC,
which seems like the perfect opportunity
to make a huge leap in
power, in efficiency,
in achieving the original mission
of doing their own Tensor chip,
and it turns out it's good.
It's a really good chip,
but it's not magic.
The main complaint that I and
other Redditors would have
about Tensor chips of the past
was that they were simply
not flagship level power
of CPU and GPU.
And this is $1,000 phone.
Like, for this price, I
could just get a Galaxy S25+
and have a Snapdragon 8 Elite,
or an iPhone 16 with an A18.
So, this new Tensor G5 is
more performant than before,
but it's not miraculously
jumping all the way to the level
of the Snapdragon 8 Elites of the world.
And I'm starting to think
that's not even really one of its goals.
Tensor G5 benchmarks
like a mid-range phone,
like the CPU is about 30%
better than last generation,
but is a solid amount still
behind the Snapdragon
chips in Samsung phones.
And it's closer to, like, the 8S Gen 4,
the one in the Nothing Phone 3.
And the GPU.
The GPU gap, if my benchmarks are correct,
are even bigger.
For some reason, Geekbench 6 OpenCL scores
are literally half of the Pixel 9s
and a full, like, 600% behind
the Snapdragon 8 Elite.
Jesus.
Its strongest area though,
is definitely the TPU,
where this one is 60% more
powerful than last generation,
and that is intentional.
This is the Tensor processing unit
that's specifically designed
to accelerate machine learning
and AI-related tasks like
running on device models,
editing photos, et cetera.
This is what Google has decided
is most important to them
with these phones and these chips.
They want them to be the fastest
and most capable AI devices.
So, in the real world,
performance wise, this Pixel 10,
it is a really smooth
phone with everyday tasks.
I've been flying around Android 16,
multitasking, flying through apps,
high refresh rate is always on.
Not even really thinking
about it too much.
It's been very fluid.
I will say though,
when I went in after a few
days into display settings
and flipped from High
resolution to Max resolution,
things sharpened up a bit,
but the phone also did get slightly,
just barely noticeably, slower.
Just a few dropped frames here and there,
which I didn't expect.
And I would also not be shocked at all
if you did head-to-head comparisons
with graphically intense games,
and frame rate measurements
of the Pixel 10
fall far behind the higher,
more powerful GPU chips.
It also lacks
hardware-accelerated ray tracing.
That's just not the big
strength of this phone.
Never has been.
And it's still a Pixel,
so I'm not expecting it ever will be.
What I can say is,
at least the battery life
for my use has been solid.
It's been solid.
I've been mostly testing the Pixel 10 Pro,
not the XL, so even on
a regular-sized phone,
I'm getting all-day battery
near dead by the end of the day,
but, like, six hours of screen-on time
and high brightness and all that.
So, it's been decently efficient.
My main concern is now shifting
to how well this phone will age,
so maybe trying to come
back to this in six months,
one year, two years, just
to see how well this does
compared to previous Pixels.
But for now, the Tensor chip,
it's not some miraculous savior
that makes it an ultra
flagship, but good chip.
Good chip.
You know what's really good, though?
Pixel Snap.
It sounds silly, but this
has genuinely become one
of my favorite new features
about the Pixel 10s.
It's just such a quality
of life improvement,
especially as someone who
is a card-carrying member
of Team No Case.
So, these phones have Qi2
wireless charging now,
and it's only at 15
watts, or 25 on the XL,
but it's so incredibly convenient
to just be able to slap the Pixel onto any
of my existing MagSafe accessories,
navigating with the phone
in the dash in the morning,
dropping the phone on a
wireless charger on my desk
where they automatically align,
keeping it topped up on a long travel trip
with my Ridge power bank.
Even if you aren't someone with a bunch
of existing MagSafe stuff sitting around,
it just opens you up to this massive world
of options for magnetic accessories
for things you can attach to your phone,
or things you can attach your phone too.
And I even think this is
actually slightly stronger
than MagSafe magnets on the iPhone,
at least with the first-party
Google accessories
they've optimized, like
with this Pixel ring stand
I got to try.
Honestly, this was the perfect
addition to this phone.
It's like it was already a phone
that didn't have very
fast wireless charging,
and so it still doesn't have
very fast wireless charging,
but it just gained a ton of functionality.
Thumbs up.
The two things that always
make a Pixel a Pixel though,
well, that would be the
cameras and the software.
So, I have good news and bad news again.
Which do you want first?
The good news.
Classic.
Yeah, the software is still awesome.
These phones all ship with
Android 16 out the box,
all of the fun material,
3 Expressive updates,
the fun smart wallpaper cutout
effects, the animations,
the haptics, the
notification jiggle physics,
all this stuff.
There's some weird stuff
that's not all perfect,
like I don't love how massive some
of the buttons are getting.
Like, okay, maybe the
Alarm app one makes sense.
Fine, make those bigger.
But the Weather app,
like this list of locations
has such massive gaps now.
So much dead white space between them.
Or the Phone app now, too.
They're making these buttons huge.
This new Gmail app,
these archive buttons
are absolutely massive.
And look at this stopwatch.
Jesus.
But, you know, for the most part,
I'm loving how colorful and clean
and fluid everything has been.
And there's so many little
things you can tweak
and poke around and have fun with.
Trust me, just watch a
few YouTube tutorials
on how to set up the
perfect quick settings
or have the ultimate
all-widgets home screen set up.
It's awesome, super flexible.
You're welcome.
And then there's all the
AI stuff on top as well
because, you know, Google.
And there's a lot of this
stuff that sort of just pops up
as you start using this phone,
and you can choose to engage with it
or just kind of ignore
it if you're not into it.
But any one of these
features could turn out to be
that awesome thing that
makes you wanna stick
with the Pixel, like Call
Screening or Now Playing.
And so, the big new one on the Pixel 10s
that's got its own section in the settings
and everything is called Magic Cue.
And this Magic Cue,
it's a very Google thing
that's supposed to take data
from across your different apps
and services and then surface
them where you need them.
At least that's what it's supposed to do.
Now, I was using this phone
and trying to get it to work.
Like I was lobbing up perfect
situations for it to kick in
and read my Gmail or read my calendar,
and then give me the
perfect text to send back,
but it rarely seemed to work
exactly the way I wanted it to
like it did in my original demos.
The thing it did the most often
was it just kept giving me a link
back to, like, open my calendar
and check for the information myself,
which is still kinda helpful,
but only half as helpful as advertised.
I have all the settings turned on,
so it's supposed to be able to
look into any of these apps,
screenshots, email, Messages,
also Keep and Contacts
and Calendar to return the answer
to the question pulled
from inside the app.
A few times, I did actually
get that to work for me,
but sometimes it was wrong.
Like I have Andrew asking me
for my flight info next week,
but it's giving me the info to
the flight I have this week,
and that would be fine
if I could go edit it
before I send it, but if I click it it,
just sends the whole thing automatically,
and doesn't also include
some of the information
I would think you want,
like the flight number.
I can see the promise here.
It feels like it's still
a work in progress.
The other thing, though, that
I found pretty interesting
was conversational editing.
It actually is coming to all
phones with Google Photos,
so it's not just, like,
a specific Pixel thing,
so I won't spend too much time on it,
but it's potentially a game changer
because it's semantic photo
editing from text prompts,
so it understands what you're asking for
and then does the editing for you,
from simple stuff like, you know,
brighten up the faces
or remove the road sign,
or even just make this picture better,
which usually does, like, a nice crop
and centers it around the subject
and evens out the exposure.
But all the way up to
complicated stuff too, like,
"Add a hot air balloon to the sky."
It'll do that.
Or, "Delete the cars
and make the sky bluer."
And then it does it.
It just does a surprisingly good job
just from hearing what you said.
Google, genuine question,
is video editing next?
Is that even possible?
Should I be concerned?
Excited?
I don't know, we'll see.
There was a couple other things
like the Journal app and NotebookLM,
which are both pre-installed
on these phones.
Also, daily briefs was
next to useless for me.
Like it's supposed to be tailored to me
and relevant to my day, but yeah,
that's not really a ton of
useful information here.
But overall, like I said,
the software is really good.
And if there's anything that
pops up that you don't like,
you can literally just ignore it.
So, that is the good news.
So then the bad news,
the cameras.
And this is where it kinda
gets a little bit weird.
It's not like they're bad cameras,
but the bad news is that it
does feel like the cameras
are slipping a little bit.
The Pixel has leaned heavily
on elite software processing for years.
They, surprise, never really
had the biggest sensors
or the best hardware,
but they pioneered HDR+,
and the Pixel camera always had this sort
of confident, contrasty look to it.
This generation of phones,
it still has that look,
but objectively speaking,
like these cameras,
they just don't stand out from the pack
nearly as much anymore.
And in some ways, they're kind
of falling behind a bit now.
Triple cameras, like I said,
are awesome to have on the base phone.
So, that 48 megapixel main camera,
the ultrawide, and the telephoto is a 5x.
And then the Pros have a bigger
50 megapixel main camera,
a bigger, higher resolution ultrawide,
and a bigger, higher resolution
5x telephoto as well.
So, regular wide shots from
the Pixel 10 and 10 Pro,
they look great.
You know, sure, the
sensor's a little smaller
on the base phone, but
they both do a great job
with sharpness and dynamic
range and lots of detail,
and usually pretty great color too.
They have that look.
Night Sight is still elite.
But past that, it's just
not good at any type of zoom
like I was hoping it would be.
The ultrawide is okay,
but usually pretty soft around the edges
with a bit more chromatic aberration
that I'm used to seeing.
And then trying to zoom in was,
like, just surprisingly bad,
at least compared to other
flagships with decent zoom.
Almost every photo I've taken,
even on these Pros that's
zoomed in, is just soft.
Like, colors would be fine
and it's bright enough,
and it's not a terrible image.
Mission still accomplished, I guess.
But, like, this super res
zoom feature on the Pros
that kicks in for everything past 30x
really feels like it encourages me
to take a bunch of Zoom
photos because once I do,
it'll run it through the
processing and sharpen things up
and resolve detail out of thin air
with a little machine learning.
But yeah, the results
just weren't that great.
I didn't even go all the way to a 100x.
All the pictures I'm taking
are, like, 30 to 50x.
And they kinda look like they have
a cartoon filter over them,
even compared to a pretty mediocre zoom
like the iPhone 16 Pro.
And it gets absolutely smoked
by a good zoom like the S25 Ultra,
even though that's more expensive.
Maybe I shouldn't be complaining
about 50x zoom photos,
maybe nobody cares,
but the sweet spot for zoom
is definitely like 5 to 10x,
or a little past that maybe.
And then the wide photos are
still obviously really good.
It's just the gaps in zoom
performance are a little weird,
considering how much it
seems to encourage me
to take zoom photos.
And then there's video performance,
which is still also beat
behind the flagships.
If you wanna see samples,
I'm planning on shooting
the next auto-focus video
on the Lucid Gravity on this phone.
So, if you care about
either Pixel 10 Pro video
or the newest, very impressive Lucid SUV,
get subscribed over there.
I'll drop a link below the like button.
But yeah, it'll be all the A-roll shots,
and then the B roll will still be
from the iPhone so you
can compare the two.
So, the Pixel 10.
It's still a Pixel,
it feels like the Pixel is a finished
slash complete thought for now,
just based on the way Google's acting
and working around this phone.
And they're not making any
big philosophical changes
to the way they attack
making a Google phone.
They're just trying again
to take it to the masses.
So, if you didn't like the Pixel last year
for certain reasons, like, you know,
"Oh, it's not the best hardware
or it's not the most powerful,"
then you still won't like the Pixel.
But if you love the Pixel
of previous years 'cause,
oh, it's this cool design that you like
or it's got great stills
or awesome software,
then you'll love this Pixel too.
Google's path of trying to bring the Pixel
to the masses is definitely challenging.
Maybe they really believe in Jimmy Fallon
and the other celebrity endorsements
that will be their savior
and finally make it happen.
Me personally, I think the
other half of their strategy
of, like, directly addressing the masses
that are on iPhones here and
giving 'em reasons to switch
with, like, Pixel Snap
and other directly
competitive parallel features,
I think that is far more interesting.
And I did just make an
entire video about this,
so I'll link this below if
you haven't seen that yet.
But the Pixel still being a Pixel
to me is mostly good news.
I really like the Pixel.
I'm probably gonna switch to
this Moonstone Pixel 10 Pro
as my main daily driver phone
and then I'm probably gonna
switch off of it to something
with more tempting,
interesting hardware features.
And then I'll probably
switch back when I get bored
with the other weird software experiences
and I want this feeling again.
And then I'll probably
switch off of it again
when it starts aging poorly.
I don't really know.
The Pixel is right where it's always been.
But you know it's not
where it's always been?
New products from channel sponsor Ridge,
like the new magnetic power
bank that works with Pixel Snap.
See, Ridge has been in the
everyday carry scene for years.
But when I joined the team,
we wanted to add a little
more tech to their lineup,
so they created the Ridge
Magnetic Power Bank.
It's a 10,000 milliamp
hour portable battery bank
that has five different
ways to charge your tech.
With Pixel Snap, you can
seamlessly connect it
to your back of your phone
and charge wirelessly.
Or if you want, you can
use the built-in wires
for 20-watt wired charging
to top up a little faster.
And it even has a nice kickstand
so you'll be able to
tackle any long plane ride
without having to sweat your battery life.
And you might be wondering,
"Why do I need a Lightning
cable if I'm a Pixel user?"
And let's be real, you
probably have some i friends,
they're probably all caught
up in their blue bubble world,
forgot to pack their chargers.
So, if you're feeling nice,
you can help them top up too.
And my favorite part is you
can charge multiple devices
at the same time with pass through,
so this ends up being a
nice little one-stop shop
for travel charging.
It comes in three sweet colors,
Basecamp Orange and also Matte Olive
and the obvious choice, Matte Black.
And if you don't love it within 99 days,
send it back, no questions asked.
So, hit over to ridge.com/mkbhd
to get 10% off your orders.
And remember, every dollar
you spend until September 15th
is more entries in the
Ridge Summer Sweepstakes.
Thanks for watching.
Catch you guys in the next one.
Peace.
(relaxing dance music)